Rockefeller Family Public Relations Department papers, Series 1-9 FA789A
Rockefeller Archive Center
- International Basic Economy Corporation (IBEC), 1947-1961; 2; 7.98 Cubic Feet 21 letter document boxes
  - General, 1947-1961; 1
    - Colombia - Arbor Acres Poultry - Avicola Colombiana, Ltd., 1961 (Box 14, Folder 130)
      IBEC and Arbor Acres Farm to develop prize chickens; other farms in Chile and Venezuela.
    - American-Colombian Corporation - Lands of Lobo in Colombia, 1956-1960 (Box 14, Folder 131)
      IBEC holds minority interest in this corporation which owns Lands of Lobo in Colombia. Stock became worthless due to adverse title decision, both LSR and NAR lost a lot of money. L. H. Levy, Jesse Knight, Jose Zaccour.
    - Ecuador - ESAM - Empress de Servicios Agricolas Mechanizados, S. A., 1950 (Box 14, Folder 132)
      Formed in 1950. Offering mechanized agricultural service on fee basis to Ecuadoran farmers - similar to Brazilian mechanized farm service co. Desire to terminate ESAM's activities - transfer of ESAM 's assets in Ecuador to Banco de Fomento. Galo Plaza, Victor Andrade, Emerick Kutschko, FAJ, F. Gardner, John E. Lockwood.
    - Peru - Le Tourneau Highway Project, 1955-1957 (Box 14, Folder 133)
      IBEC wanted to keep informed of progress, no real interest. Art Anderson.
    - ECOR, Inc. (Economic Research), 1949-1950 (Box 14, Folder 134)
      To explore development possibilities in South America - purely research and study operation. Control of ECOR evenly divided 3 ways: Nelson's group, South American group headed by Dasso of Peru and European group headed by Matteoli.
    - Bangkok, Thailand - Economic Development Corp., 1957-1958 (Box 14, Folder 135)
      IBEC acquired controlling interest - Economic Development represents leading American and European firms involved in agricultural and industrial development projects in Thailand, Cambodia, Laos, South Vietnam; Also conducts import-export business. EDC branching out to work with AOFC, V.D. Anderson Co. Robert Weber, Steven David.
    - Statements on Sale of IBEC Companies to Local National Investors, 1959 (Box 14, Folder 136)
    - IDD - Industrial Development Division, 1958-1960 (Box 14, Folder 137)
      IBEC to make available its industrial development experience to outside clients who are interested in expanding their activities. ARAMCO and IDD. Flick, K. G. and IDD. IDD brochure. Steven David.
    - Investment Employment Contract. Investimentos e Administracao IBEC S. A., 1956 (Box 15, Folder 138)
      Offering investment services, contract.
    - Transoceanic - AOFC, Ltd., 1955-1961 (Box 15, Folder 139)
      (Formerly Transoceanic Development Corp. and American overseas Finance Co.) 1955 Transoceanic Develop. Corp formed as Canadian Corporation to acquire equity investments in foreign countries. 1957 IBEC and CIT Financial Corp. purchased assets of AOFC (Transoceanic among members of purchasing group) AOIC. 1960 - consolidation. Cuban takeover of Antillian Steel. IBEC acquisition of Transoceanic - AOFC. FAJ, J. Richardson Dilworth, Steven David.
    - Avila Hotel - Caracas, Venezuela, 1951-1955 (Box 15, Folder 140)
      Sale of common stock by IBEC in Companina Anonima Hotelera Venezolana (which operates Avila Hotel) to Venezuelan group. FAJ, Bernardo Jofre, Bill Coles.
    - Avila Oil Company, 1952 (Box 15, Folder 141)
      Joint enterprise with Mr. Chester M. Crebbs, former pres.of Meme Grande Oil Co., and IBEC. Avila organized primarily to engage in geological exploration and to purchase oil royalties, leases and farm-outs.
    - Brassert Project, 1947-1948 (Box 15, Folder 142)
      Supposed to have been joint enterprise with IBEC and Corporazion Venezolana de Fomento of pilot plant operation in US to test process for reduction of iron ore by use of natural gas; never seems to have materialized. Fred Gardner, FAJ, Bernardo Jofre.
    - The Bellows Company, 1957-1961 (Box 15, Folder 143)
      IBEC acquisition of Bellows Co. of Akron, Ohio. Manufacturer of pneumatic, hydraulic and electrical equipment for automated production in practically every industry. L. H. Levy, Robert Purcell, Steven David, H. B. Link.
    - Coffee - General, 1950-1955 (Box 15, Folder 144)
      Coffee prices much too high - US Government concern. IBEC studies. Government controls over speculation and future trading on coffee. Situation and circumstances of Brazilian coffee growers. Fred Gardner, B. Friele, Steven David, FAJ.
    - Productos de Cafe, S. A. - El Salvador, 1955-1960 (Box 15, Folder 145)
      Coffee producers - joint enterprise of IBEC, Tenco, Inc. of New Jersey and Compania de Inversiones, S. A. representing group of Salvadorean investors, instant coffee plant, outskirts of San Salvador. Fred Garner, FAJ, Steven David.
    - General Coffee Company, Inc., 1956-1958 (Box 15, Folder 146)
      To provide eating establishments and institutions with automatic coffee making machines. IBEC with Martinson's Coffee of New York and John H. Wilkins Co. of Washington, D. C. Financial statement 1958 - loss. Steven David, FAJ, Theodore Streibert.
    - IBENCO, 1956-1957 (Box 15, Folder 147)
      IBEC and TENCO, Inc. of Linden, New Jersey formed IBENCO, a corporation to blend, package and distribute soluble coffee on worldwide basis. Percy H. Clark, Jr., Walter S. Wolff
    - Gould Paper Co. - Lyons Falls Paper Co., 1950-1956 (Box 15, Folder 148)
      Prompted by world shortage of newsprint. Gould Paper Co. of Lyons Falls, NY acquired by IBEC and group organized by C. T. Janer of Rio de Janeiro, Brazil and Ralph W. Luethi of Utica, New York. IBEC sold its interest to Lyons Falls Paper Co.
    - IBEC Agricultural Services - IAS, 1953 (Box 15, Folder 149)
      Management services for NAR's Venezuelan farms. Robert Fulton.
    - ILAPECA - Industrias Lacteas de Perijaca., 1947-1952 (Box 15, Folder 150)
      Plant producing whole powered milk established by IBEC, Foremost Dairies and Venezuelan milk producers. Golden State Milk Co. joining with IBEC also in Venezuela.
    - Rollins Burdick Hunter, C. A., 1957-1959 (Box 15, Folder 151)
      IBEC established Insurance brokerage company in Caracas to handle full line of general insurance. Charles G. Mock, FAJ, Steven David.
    - Policies and Procedures, 1947 (Box 15, Folder 152-154)
    - Press Releases, 1947-1948 (Box 16, Folder 155-156)
      Fish company, Food Production Inc., food distribution, IBEC Brazil, milk company, Russell, Serra, transportation, VBEC Incorporation.
    - Press Releases - Ecuador, 1948 (Box 16, Folder 157)
    - Press Releases - Pending, 1947-1948 (Box 16, Folder 158)
    - Projects - General, 1946-1947 (Box 16, Folder 159)
    - Projects - Cargill - Grain Elevators, 1948 (Box 16, Folder 160)
    - Projects - Fertilizer Experiments, 1946-1947 (Box 16, Folder 161)
    - Projects - Manker - Trucking, 1947 (Box 16, Folder 162)
    - Sinclair-Collins Valve Company - Akron, Ohio, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 163)
      IBEC desired acquisition of Sinclair-Collins, major manufacturer of control values for steam, air, liquid and gas used extensively in rubber, plastics and plywood industries. Draft release. H. B. Link, Steven David, FAJ.
    - Tanganika Concessions - Africa, 1950 (Box 16, Folder 164)
      IBEC investment in Tanganika Concessions, a holding and development co. with interests in Africa.
    - "VEFISA" - Venezolana de Financiamiento, S. A., 1955 (Box 16, Folder 165)
      Venezuela Finance Company formed by IBEC with Canadian private capital group. J. W. Hisle, Bernardo Jofre.
  - Brazil and Venezuela, 1947-1958; 2
    - Brazil - General, 1947-1961 (Box 17, Folder 166)
      Formation, press release. Brazilian newspaper comment. Difficulties of various IBEC operations in Brazil, PR policy. Stock sales, budgets. K. J. Kadow, MD, FAJ, Arthur Vandenberg Jr., S. G. Palmgren
    - Brazil - Field Reports, 1947-1948 (Box 17, Folder 167)
      1947: Semi-monthly reports on status of each IBEC project in Brazil. 1948: Weekly reports, same general format and objective as semi-monthly reports. K. J. Kadow, Dee W. Jackson, Morrison Tucker, Edwina Barbara.
    - Brazil - Nelson J. Riley, 1947-1949 (Box 17, Folder 168)
      In charge of all field public relations in Brazil and Venezuela. Establishing a consensus on public relations policy between NY and South America, problems. MD, FAJ, Nelson Riley.
    - Brazil - Richard Aldrich Reports, 1950-1951 (Box 17, Folder 169)
      Aldrich absorbed into Brazil office - weekly news reports on significant Brazilian developments.
    - Brazil - Cargill Agricola e Comercial (CACSA), 1949-1957 (Box 17, Folder 170)
      Exporting of corn to foreign countries, exchange for goods i.e.. wine, car parts, etc. Problem of hurting small Brazilian farmer in prices. Senate grain investigations Committee, charges of price manipulation by illegal trading. Continental Grain Co. purchase of CACSA. FAJ, Steven David, W. D. Bradford, Arthur Vandenburg, Jr.
    - Brazil - Companhia Empreendimentos e Administracao (CEA), 1950-1958 (Box 17, Folder 171)
      Furnish financial administration and guidance to Brazilian, American and European Interests - services available to companies seeking money for development or expansion of interests in Brazil. Richard Aldrich - Director. FAJ, Rankin Roberts, Henry Bagley, Richard Aldrich.
    - Brazil - Empressa de Mechanizacao Agricola, S.A. (EMA), 1948-1952 (Box 17, Folder 172)
      To offer mechanized agricultural services (plowing, dicing, planting, etc.) to farmers.
    - Brazil - EMA Article by Dr. J. B. Griffing, 1951 (Box 17, Folder 173)
    - Brazil - Fazenda Bodoquena, S. A., 1956-1957 (Box 17, Folder 174)
      A Brazilian cattle ranch. 10 percent IBEC and members of family, 60 percent. Walther Moreira Salles. Federal Frontier Zone Commission approval. Strong "anti-imperialist" feelings in Brazil causes them to move cautiously. FAJ, Henry W. Bagley.
    - Brazil - Fundo Crescinco (FC), 1959-1961 (Box 17, Folder 175)
      An open-end mutual fund-financing company
    - Brazil - HELICO, 1949 (Box 17, Folder 176)
      Helicopter dusting service, liquidated. FAJ, Arthur Vandenburg.
    - Brazil - Industria Metalurgica Forjaco, S. A., 1952-1953 (Box 17, Folder 177)
      Drop forging plant, First major one in Brazil, IBEC stockholder.
    - Brazil - Industria de Roupas Regencia, S. A., 1949-1950 (Box 17, Folder 178)
      Manufacture of clothing.
    - Brazil - Potassa e Adubos Quimicos do Brasil, S. A. (PEAQ), 1950 (Box 17, Folder 179)
    - Brazil - SAFAP, 1950 (Box 17, Folder 180)
      Hog raising company, termination of activities. Arthur Vandenburg.
    - Brazil - SASA, 1950-1954 (Box 17, Folder 181)
      Hybrid seed corn development, sales problem. Fred Gardner, Henry Bagley, FAJ.
    - Brazil - Serra da Bocaina, 1947 (Box 17, Folder 182)
      Long range goal - agricultural development - first, opening land to charcoal and lumber development. K. J. Kadow, J. B. Griffing, W. D. Bradford.
    - Brazil - Thela Commercial, 1949-1952 (Box 18, Folder 183)
      IBEC bought into Thela to secure profits for paying its operating expenses - not part of IBEC philosophy. Discusses matter of IBEC taking minority positions in Brazilian enterprises. FAJ, Fred Gardner, Dr. T. Quartim Barbosa.
    - Brazil - Chase Investment Bank, 1951 (Box 18, Folder 184)
      Entry of Chase Bank into the Brazilian investment field. Attacks by the Brazilian press. FAJ, Henry Bagley, Gilbert H. Clee, Arthur Vandenburg.
    - Brazil - Inter-Americana Finance and Investment Company, 1953-1957 (Box 18, Folder 185)
      Investment Banking concern, Chase Bank a shareholder. Proposed re-organization of Inter-Americana. FAJ, Fred Gardner, MD.
    - VBEC - Certificate of Incorporation, By-Laws, 1947-1950 (Box 18, Folder 186)
    - VBEC - General, 1947-1953 (Box 18, Folder 187)
      Early developments of program in Venezuela. Newspaper comment. Arrangement for support of VBEC with Venezuelan government. Basic PR principles of VBEC for Venezuela. Possibility of merging VBEC and IBEC. NAR, FAJ.
    - VBEC - Annual Reports, 1949-1953 (Box 18, Folder 188)
    - VBEC - Financial, 1950-1956 (Box 18, Folder 189)
      Budgets, financial statements. J. W. Hisle.
    - VBEC - Saks 5th Avenue Site, Purchase of, 1953 (Box 18, Folder 190)
      VBEC bought site of Saks store (East side 5th Ave. between 49 and 50th) as an investment, sold by William Zeckendorf. Does not change Saks lease (until 2027).
    - VBEC - Oil Companies, 1947-1953 (Box 18, Folder 191)
      Financial commitments to VBEC. Oil companies approval of Cert. of Inc., cooperation in wholesaling food project. VBEC reorganization - oil companies getting out of VBEC enterprises. Participating oil companies: Creole, Mene Grande, Caribbean Petroleum. William Coles, John E. Lockwood.
    - VBEC - Venezuela Oil Imports - Jofre and Reynolds, 1953 (Box 18, Folder 192)
      Venezuelan reaction to US proposals for limiting oil imports.
    - VBEC - Compania Anonima Distribuidora de Alimentos (CADA), 1947-1960 (Box 18, Folder 193)
      Project Proposal, for the warehousing and distribution of foodstuffs in Venezuela. Power struggle in CADA creates serious problems in management. Financial problems, operating problems. Anthony B. Toto. R. W. Boogaart, Bernardo Jofre, NAR, Fred Gardner, FAJ.
    - VBEC - Compania Anonima Lactuaria del Caribe - Project Proposal, 1947 (Box 19, Folder 194-195)
      To provide equipment and means to reconstitute whole milk powder into fluid milk; to produce and distribute ice cream with same facilities.
    - VBEC - Compania Anonima Productora de Alimentos (CAPA) - Project Proposal, 1947 (Box 19, Folder 196)
      CAPA to be a subsidiary of VBEC - agricultural production of basic foods i.e.. livestock, dairy products, poultry, vegetables, etc.
    - VBEC - Compania Anonima de Pesca y Productor Congelados - (CAPCO) - Project Proposal, 1947 (Box 19, Folder 197)
      To enter Venezuelan fishing industry to increase production, improve quality and lower prices.
    - VBEC - S. A. Formento Agro-Pecuario - Project Proposal, 1947 (Box 19, Folder 198)
      To establish farms on profitable basis for economic production of hogs and their feed, to combat hog cholera and for production of good breeding stock and demonstration of techniques of good breeding of hogs.
    - VBEC - Warehouse Survey, 1949 (Box 19, Folder 199)
      Caracas, Maracaibo and Puerta La Cruz, Venezuela. Richard R. Klinck and Paul B. Christensen.
    - VBEC - Productora Agropecuaria C. A. (PACA) - Project Proposal, 1947 (Box 19, Folder 200)
      For food production of wide range of products suited to Venezuelan climate, terrain, etc. Description of company and operations. Financial difficulties. Possibility of terminating activities in US or changing nature of company, arrangements with VBEC. Bob Russell, Fred Gardner, FAJ.
    - VBEC - Pesquerias Caribe Compania Anonima (PESCA), 1948 (Box 19, Folder 201)
      Engaged in fishing activities to increase production, improve facilities for transportation, establish refrigeration service and lower prices for consumers. FAJ, Francis W. Taylor.
    - VBEC - Sementes Agroceres S. A.- Project Proposal, 1947 (Box 20, Folder 202)
      To produce and market hybrid seed corn and other seeds which may be appropriate in connection with hybrid seed corn production.
    - VBEC - Merchandise Division, 1950-1954 (Box 20, Folder 203)
      Buys foodstuffs and other consumer goods in US and reassembles these for export abroad - substantial volume in Venezuela. J. F. Brady, Fred Gardner, E. D. Van Wagner, J. Weldon George
    - VBEC - Bolivian Operations, 1953 (Box 20, Folder 204)
      VBEC merchandise division, going to handle spot purchases of foodstuffs and related items for Bolivian government or any corporation owned by it. Victor Andrade.
    - VBEC - Films, "The Battle for Food", 1948-1950 (Box 20, Folder 205)
      Princeton Film Center produced film "The Battle for Food" on VBEC for 5000 in 1949. In 1950 desire to enlarge film into more elaborate production; asked bids of Princeton Film Center and RKO Pa.the, Inc. - turned down Princeton. Shooting script of Princeton's original version. Schuyler Bradt, Gordon Knox, FAJ, M. Clay Adams.
    - VBEC - Monthly Progress Reports, 1949 (Box 20, Folder 206-208)
      March-May
    - VBEC - Monthly Progress Reports, 1949 (Box 21, Folder 209-212)
      June-September
    - VBEC - Press Releases, 1947-1948 (Box 21, Folder 213)
  - IBEC Technical Services (ITSC), 1947-1953; 3
    - General, 1947 (Box 21, Folder 214)
      General description, ITSC was organized in 1947 to provide technical services, mainly in public works and economic development; services on fee basis.
    - Annual Reports, 1949-1950 (Box 21, Folder 215)
    - Active Projects, 1948-1949 (Box 21, Folder 216)
      Brief run-downs of projects that were currently active.
    - Certificate of Incorporation - By-Laws, 1947 (Box 21, Folder 217)
    - Cuba, "Economic Development in Cuba" - A Report for the Chase National Bank - Stacy May, 1948 (Box 22, Folder 218-219)
      Extensive report on Cuba's economic structure.
    - Sao Paulo, Brazil Survey - Robert Moses, 1950-1951 (Box 22, Folder 220)
      Under IBEC supervision, ITSC to do survey on possible city-wide public improvements for Sao Paulo. Robert Moses to head group of engineers and technicians from US who will do actual survey. Strong criticism and attacks on plan not only from Brazilian press but from groups in Sao Paulo section of Institute of Architects of Brazil. Main points of criticism: plan tells them nothing they don't already know, resents foreign intrusion, foreigners ignorant of socio-economic conditions in Brazil which may or may not make such a plan possible. Robert Moses, L. Prestes, FAJ, Henry Bagley, Arthur Vandenburg.
    - Sao Paulo, Brazil Tramway, Light and Power Co., 1949-1951 (Box 22, Folder 221)
      Madigan-Hyland to do a survey of its undevelopment in land that it owns.
    - Madigan-Hyland Corporation, 1947-1951 (Box 22, Folder 222)
      ITSC set up this corporation with Mitchael J. Madigan and Richard V. Hyland as its engineering arm; ITSC to own 49 percent of it.
    - Port of LaGuaira - Venezuela, 1947 (Box 22, Folder 223)
      Survey on expansion and reorganization.
    - Caracas - La Guaira Highway, 1949 (Box 22, Folder 224)
      ITSC and Madigan to submit resume in answer to an advertisement. IBEC - ITSC - DeLeuw Cather - Traffic and Transit Survey - Caracas. 1948. ITSC with Corporacion Fomento to do traffic and transit survey of Caracas. Transit survey done by DeLeuw Cather, Chicago engineering firm; traffic survey by Robert Moses, City Park Commissioner and Construction Coordinator for NYC.
    - Transit and Traffic Study - Bogata, Colombia, 1949 (Box 22, Folder 225)
      Transit portion similar to study in Caracas but traffic portion different in that no question re city plan included.
    - Newfoundland, 1949-1951 (Box 22, Folder 226)
      Joseph Smallwood - Prime Minister of Province of Newfoundland - ITSC started general economic survey in 1950. Joseph R. Smallwood.
    - Guatemalan Water-Way and Port, 1949 (Box 22, Folder 227)
      Livingston Bay - El Estor Waterway Report.
    - Press Releases, 1948-1950 (Box 22, Folder 228-229)
      General, Brazil Airport, traffic survey, Don Hatch
    - Projects, 1947-1949 (Box 23, Folder 230)
      LaGuaira Port survey, shoe industry, traffic, housing.
    - S9-VEN Fishing Boat Building and Repairing Survey, 1948 (Box 23, Folder 231)
      Report on installation of fishing boat bldg.and repair yard at Porlamar, Isla Margarita, Venezuela.
    - Trans-Arabian Highway, 1953 (Box 23, Folder 232)
      Decision to drop project at that time, reason: question of timing in relation to troubled conditions of the Middle East area. LH Levy, John French, FAJ, George Dudley.
    - Shoe Report - Venezuela, 1948 (Box 23, Folder 233-234)
      Russell A.Walkey conducted the survey for ITSC - desire to increase production so as to make low-cost shoes available to as many persons in Venezuela as possible. PR desire to tone down criticism, esp. in re to health problem. Copy of report. MD, Russell A.Walkey, Fred Gardner, G. A. Dudley.
    - Belgium - Blaton-Aubert, 1949-1950 (Box 23, Folder 235)
      ITSC agreement with Blaton-Aubert under which it will perform services in US in connection with construction by Blaton-Aubert of a refinery in Belgium for Esso Refining Co. provided that contract for this construction was given to Blaton-Aubert. C. B. F. Brill.
    - India - Kandla, India, 1950 (Box 23, Folder 236)
      After partition of India, desire on part of government of India to develop Kandla as second major port on its west coast. Wants ITSC to draw up a plan for Kandla's development. Gautam Sarabhai, G. A. Dudley.
    - Iran - Max W. Thornburg, 1948 (Box 23, Folder 237)
      Max Thornburg, foreign industrial consultant, trying to interest ITSC in doing some consulting and supervising of Iran Seven Years Plan. ITSC's decision not to take on project. FAJ.
  - IBEC Housing Corporation (IHC), 1949-1957; 4
    - General, 1950-1961 (Box 23, Folder 238)
      To provide adequate shelter through low and medium priced homes - majority of IBEC's housing in Puerto Rico. Proposal to dissolve IBEC housing in 1960. Customer service. WR loan. Descriptive pamphlets. Winthrop Rockefeller, FAJ, NAR, Saul Richman.
    - Annual Reports, 1949-1957 (Box 23, Folder 239)
    - Informe, 1949-1956 (Box 23, Folder 240)
    - Ceylon Proposal, 1950 (Box 23, Folder 241)
      Low Cost Housing for Ceylon proposal booklet. George A. Dudley, (Pres.)
    - Chile, 1950-1960 (Box 23, Folder 242)
      Housing project under discussion 1950, asking for Point IV funds for US personnel for project. Draft letter in 1950 turning down project in Chile. 1960 signing of agreement for construction of 700 low-cost homes in Santiago. Pres. Gonzalez-Videla.
    - Cuba - Webb and Knapp Project, 1956 (Box 23, Folder 243)
      Studying the possibility of Cuban housing - with the Zeckendorfs. Harry T. Newcomb.
    - El Salvador, 1952-1954 (Box 23, Folder 244)
      1952 - 3 projects: new town for earthquake victims in Valle de la Esperanza; 1000 bed hospital in San Salvador and master plan for San Miquel. Gaxcia Prieto, MD, Edward Echeverria, George Dudley, FAJ, WR, Robert Fulton
    - Iran, 1958 (Box 23, Folder 245)
      Agreement: IHD with DRC (Development and Resources Corporation) to remedy housing problem in Khuzestan area of Iran
    - Iraq, 1954-1956 (Box 24, Folder 246)
      Report of Iraq Housing Mission. George Dudley.
    - Israel - Amun-Israeli Housing Corp., 1949-1951 (Box 24, Folder 247)
      Amun-Israeli Housing Corp. set up by David Dubinsky's Union, ILGWU, to sell bonds for investment in housing in Israel. NAR investment 100,000 dollars and is on Board of Directors. G. A. Dudley.
    - Puerto Rico - Releases, 1954-1961 (Box 24, Folder 248)
    - Puerto Rico - Villa Las Lomas, Lomas Verdes and Altamesa, 1954-1961 (Box 24, Folder 249)
      Brochures, clippings, pamphlets. In Metropolitan San Juan projected 1800 unit housing development. Financed under the mortgage guarantee system of FHA. Roger H. Corbetta (Corbetta Construction) Problem over PR 1961 summary of development in Puerto Rico. Parkville. William V. Reed, MD, George Dudley.
    - Puerto Rico - ILGWU, 1956-1957 (Box 24, Folder 250)
      International Ladies Garment Workers' union purchasing 2,600,000 dollars in mortgages in housing project developed by IHC, called Santiago Iglesias. David Dubinsky, FAJ, MD, Dr. Santiago Iglesias, Jr.
    - Puerto Rico - Churches - Church Properties, 1955-1957 (Box 24, Folder 251)
      Trying to decide about making sites available for churches to purchase; inter-denominational. Requests from clergy in Puerto Rico for church sites. Roger Corbetta, George Dudley, Bill Reed.